David Mozersky African Union High-Level Implementation Panel Papers MS205
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Sudan Post-referendum negotiation files, 1998 -- 2012; MS205.004; 405 Digital Object(s)
  - Lead panel, 1998 -- 2012; MS205.004.00085
    - Post-July Negotiations, 2011 -- 2012; MS205.004.00426
      - Proposal on Transitional Financial Arrangements and Some Other Matters, 2011-11-14; MS205.004.00431
      - Draft Terms of Agreement between the Republic of Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan Concerning Oil, Transitional Viability Agreements and Other Related Issues, 2012-02-03; MS205.004.00432
      - Draft Roadmap for Final Agreement on Oil, 2012-02-03; MS205.004.00433
      - Adoption of Implementation Matrix by the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-03-12; MS205.004.00434
        Abyei (Sudan); Security; Citizenship; Boundary disputes; Trade Policy; Banks and banking, Central; Pensions; Assets and liabilities; Petroleum industry and trade
      - Agreement between the Republic of Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan on the Demarcation of the Boundary, 2012-03-13; MS205.004.00435
      - Framework Agreement on the Status of Nationals of the Other State and Related Matters between the Republic of Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-03-13; MS205.004.00436
      - AUHIP Press Statement - Agreements on the Status of Nationals and Demarcation of the Common Boundary, 2012-03-13; MS205.004.00437
        Sudan; South Sudan; Boundaries; Citizenship; Joint Border Commission; Joint Demarcation Committee
      - The Agreement on Friendly Relations and Cooperation (AFRC) between the Republic of South Sudan and the Republic of Sudan - A Republic of South Sudan Proposal, 2012-07; MS205.004.00438
      - Summary of the Proposed "Agreement on Friendly Relations and Cooperation" Between the Republic of South Sudan and the Republic of Sudan, 2012-07; MS205.004.00439
      - South Sudan Presents it Proposed "Agreement on Friendly Relations&Cooperation between the Republic of South Sudan and the Republic of Sudan" (AFRC) - Press Release, 2012-07-23; MS205.004.00440
        Sudan; South Sudan; Reconciliation; Interstate relations--Sudan
      - The Position of the Government of the Sudan on the Outstanding Issues, 2012-08-03; MS205.004.00441
        Abyei (Sudan); Sudan; South Sudan; Nīl al Azraq (Sudan); Kurdufān al-Janūbīyah (Sudan); Negotiation--Sudan; Border security; Security; Boundaries; Interstate relations--Sudan; Conflict Management; Petroleum industry and trade; Trade Policy
      - Peace and Security Council - 329th Meeting - Communique, 2012-08-03; MS205.004.00442
        Abyei (Sudan); Sudan; South Sudan; Nīl al Azraq (Sudan); Kurdufān al-Janūbīyah (Sudan); Borderlands; Security; Petroleum industry and trade; African Union. Peace and Security Council
      - Memorandum of Understanding between the Sudan People's Liberation Movement/North and the African Union/League of Arab States/United Nations Tripartite on Humanitarian Assistance to War-Affected Civilians in Blue Nile and South Kordofan States, 2012-08-04; MS205.004.00443
        Sudan; South Sudan; Nīl al Azraq (Sudan); Kurdufān al-Janūbīyah (Sudan); Humanitarian Assistance; Security; Sudan People's Liberation Movement-North; African Union; League of Arab States. Idārat Filas_īn
      - Draft Agreement between the Government of Sudan and the Sudan People's Liberation Movement-North for the Resolution of the Conflict in Blue Nile and Southern Kordofan States and Related Issues, 2012-09-17; MS205.004.00444
      - Proposal on the Final Status of the Abyei Area, 2012-09-21; MS205.004.00445
      - Government of Sudan Response to the AUHIP - Possible Options of the Final Status of the Abyei Area and Proposal on the Referendum Presented to the Addis Ababa Summit, 2012-09-23 -- 2012-09-25; MS205.004.00446
      - Agreement between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan on Border Issues, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00447
        Agreement on border issues between Sudan and South Sudan.
        Sudan; South Sudan; Borderlands; Border security; Boundaries; Transhumance
      - Framework Agreement on the Status of Nationals of the Other State and Related Matters between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00448
      - Agreement between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan on Certain Economic Matters, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00449
        Agreement between Sudan and South Sudan on certain economic issues, including the treatment of external and domestic assets and liabilities; state archives and cultural heritage property.
        Sudan; South Sudan; Debts, External; Archives--Sudan; Cultural heritage; Reconciliation; Domestic Assets and Liabilities
      - Agreement on a Framework for Cooperation on Central Banking Issues between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00450
        The agreement establishes the Joint Central Banks Committee (JCBC).
        Sudan; South Sudan; Banks and banking, Central; Commercial banks; Monetary policy
      - Agreement between the Government of the Republic of South Sudan and the Government of the Republic of the Sudan on Oil and Related Economic Matters, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00451
        Sudan; South Sudan; Petroleum pipelines--Fees; Transportation--Equipment and supplies--Tariff; Natural resources; Petroleum industry and trade; Borderlands; Reconciliation
      - Framework Agreement to Facilitate Payment of Post Service Benefits between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00452
        Sudan; South Sudan; Public service; Public servants; Pensions; Pensioners
      - Agreement on Trade and Trade Related Issues between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00453
        The agreement determines that each State will pursue an independent national trade policy and establishes a Joint Ministerial Committee on Trade Relations.
        Sudan; South Sudan; International Trade; Trade Policy; Joint Ministerial Committee on Trade Relations
      - The Cooperation Agreement between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00454
        Sudan; South Sudan; Abyei (Sudan); Interstate relations--Sudan; Border security; Citizenship; Petroleum industry and trade; Banks and banking, Central; Pensions
      - Agreement on Security Arrangements between the Republic of the Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan, 2012-09-27; MS205.004.00455
        Sudan; South Sudan; Border security; Demilitarized zone; Borderlands
  - Political Committee, 2011; MS205.004.00456
    - Annotated Agenda for the Chair SPLM/NCP Political Committee Meeting 6-7 April 2011, 2011-04-06 -- 2011-04-07; MS205.004.00457
    - Proposed Agenda for the Meeting of the SPLM/NCP Political Committee Meeting, 2011-03-24; MS205.004.00458
  - Security, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.004.00459
    - Agreement between the Government of Sudan and the Government of Southern Sudan on Border Security and the Joint Political and Security Mechanism, 2011-06-29; MS205.004.00460
    - Joint Position Paper on Border Security - Post-Referendum Negotiations Security Cluster, 2011-05-30; MS205.004.00461
    - Agreement between the Republic of Sudan and the Republic of South Sudan on Border Monitoring Support Mission - Kadugli, Sudan, 2011-08-08; MS205.004.00462
    - Report of the 9th Meeting of the Joint Security Cluster - Post Referendum Negotiations - Juba, 2010-12-06 -- 2010-12-07; MS205.004.00463
    - Agreement on the Border Monitoring Support Mission between the Government of Sudan and the Government of South Sudan - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2011-07-30; MS205.004.00464
    - SKS SIT Map, 2011-06-20; MS205.004.00465
    - Two Areas Security Negotiations - Plan of Action - AUHIP Confidential, 2011-04-19; MS205.004.00466
    - Report Workshop on Security Arrangements in the Two Areas - AUHIP Confidential - Addis Ababa, 2011-04-18 -- 2011-04-19; MS205.004.00467
    - Border Security Management - Plan of Action - AUHIP Confidential, 2011-04-19; MS205.004.00468
    - JM Recommendation to Widen Talks on Two States, 2011-06-27; MS205.004.00469
  - Strategy papers, 2011; MS205.004.00470
    - Point of Agreement on Abyei, 2011-01-23; MS205.004.00471
    - Assets and Liabilities, 2011-01-10; MS205.004.00472
    - A Strategy for Negotiations on Economic Issues, 2011-01-10; MS205.004.00473
    - A Strategy for Negotiations on Economic Issues - January 17, 2011, 2011-01-17; MS205.004.00474
    - Preliminary Comments and Reflections on the Current Situation - Negotiation Crisis, 2011-03-13; MS205.004.00475
  - UK letters to Thabo Mbeki, 2011; MS205.004.00476
    - Letter from Andrew Mitchell (UKAID Secretary of State) to Thabo Mbeki (Chair AUHIP), 2011-02-07; MS205.004.00477
    - High-Level Symposium on Border Management and Security - Schedule, 2011-02-23 -- 2011-02-24; MS205.004.00478
    - Draft Letter from Thabo Mbeki to Andrew Mitchel (Secretary of State), 2011-02; MS205.004.00479
- RAND-HU research papers, 2009 -- 2010; MS205.005; 52 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains research papers written by RAND Corporation. These research papers are primarily case studies of other countries who faced issues similar to those of Sudan and South Sudan. They analyze how those countries addressed the problems in order to provide the AUHIP team with guidance in their mediation efforts.
  - Assets and Liabilities, 2009; MS205.005.00001
    - Policy Guide to Assets and Liabilities, 2009-07; MS205.005.00002; Humanity United
    - The Dissolution of Czechoslovakia - Division of Assets and Liabilities, 2009-06; MS205.005.00003; Humanity United
    - Secession of Eritrea from Ethiopia - The Consequence of Failing to Negotiate Further Issues, 2009-07; MS205.005.00004; Humanity United
    - The Devision of Assets and Liabilities After the Breakup of the Soviet Union, 2009-07; MS205.005.00005; Humanity United
    - Serbia and Montenegro: Division of Assets and Liabilities, 2009-07; MS205.005.00006; Humanity United
  - Citizenship rights, 2009; MS205.005.00007
    - Citizenship Rights in Sudan: Prospects for Post-Independence South, 2009-12; MS205.005.00008; Humanity United
    - Policy Guide to Models of Citizenship, 2009-12; MS205.005.00009; Humanity United
  - Currency and Finance, 2009; MS205.005.00010
    - Policy Guide to Currency and Financial Arrangements, 2009-12; MS205.005.00011; Humanity United
    - Czechoslovakia - Monetary Arrangements after Dissolution, 2009-12; MS205.005.00012; Humanity United
    - Estonia - Monetary Arrangements after Independence, 2009-12; MS205.005.00013; Humanity United
    - Eritrea - Monetary Arrangements after Independence from Ethiopia, 2009-12; MS205.005.00014; Humanity United
    - Latvia - Monetary Arrangements after Independence, 2009-12; MS205.005.00015; Humanity United
  - Matrix documents, 2010; MS205.005.00016
    - Sudan Post-2011 Matrix, 2010-02; MS205.005.00017
    - Summary of Sudan Post 2011 Issues to be Negotiated (Priorities, Linkages), 2010-01; MS205.005.00018
  - Oil and pipline option papers, 2009; MS205.005.00019
    - Paper One: Examples of International Pipelines, 2009-06; MS205.005.00020; Humanity United
    - Paper Two: Applied Lessons from Other Pipelines for Post-2011 Sudan, 2009-06; MS205.005.00021; Humanity United
    - Pipeline Mapping Exercise, 2009-07; MS205.005.00022; Humanity United
  - Oil Case Studies, 2009; MS205.005.00023
    - The Chad-Cameroon Petroleum Development and Pipeline Project (CCPP), 2009-02; MS205.005.00024
    - Overview Paper on Cross-Border Oil Revenue Sharing Models: Options, Common Lessons, and Potential Applicability to Sudan, 2009-02; MS205.005.00025
    - Avoiding the Resource Curse: Profile of Resource Revenue Funds, 2009-02; MS205.005.00026
    - Joint Development Zone between Sao Tome and Principe and Nigeria, 2009-02; MS205.005.00027
    - Historial Anomaly Necessitates Unique Arrangement: Oil Production in the Saudi-Kuwaiti Neutral Zone, 2009-02; MS205.005.00028
    - Good Model, Modest Success: Revenue Sharing from Transfrontier Wildlife Reserves in Southern Africa, 2009-02; MS205.005.00029
    - Timor Leste: Revenue Sharing, 2009-02; MS205.005.00030
    - Many Opportunities for Failure, but Ultimately Success: TransMed Pipeline, 2009-02; MS205.005.00031
    - Cross-Border Cooperation in Petroleum Development: The UK-Norway Example, 2009-02; MS205.005.00032
  - Popular consultations, 2009; MS205.005.00033
    - East Timor's Popular Consultation Process, 2009-12; MS205.005.00034
    - Policy Guide to Popular Consultation, 2009-12; MS205.005.00035
    - Rwanda's Popular Consultation Process, 2009-12; MS205.005.00036
    - South Africa's Popular Consultation Process, 2009-12; MS205.005.00037
  - Population case studies, 2009; MS205.005.00038
    - Nigeria and Cameroon and the Bakassi Peninsula, 2009-02; MS205.005.00039
    - Nigeria - Cameroom and the Bakassi Peninsula: A Successful Transfer of Sovereignty but Some Challenges in Transitioning the Population, 2009-02; MS205.005.00040
    - Native American Tribues of United States and Canada, 2009-02; MS205.005.00041
    - Fulbe of Ghana and Cote D'Ivoire, 2009-02; MS205.005.00042
    - Policy Suggestions for Pastoralist Issues, 2009-07; MS205.005.00043
    - Native American Indians of United States and Mexico, 2009-02; MS205.005.00044
    - Overview Paper on Managing Cross-Border Population Models: Options, Common Lessons and Potential Applicability to Sudan, 2009-02; MS205.005.00045
    - Sami of Norway, Sweden, Finland and Russia, 2009-02; MS205.005.00046
  - Refugees, 2009; MS205.005.00047
    - Bosnia and Herzegovina: Settling the Displaced Amidst Ethnic Warfare, 2009-06; MS205.005.00048; Humanity United
    - Georgia and Abkhazia: Secession and Refugees amid Ongoing Conflict, 2009-06; MS205.005.00049; Humanity United
    - Partition of British India: Population Movements and Refugee Issues, 2009-06; MS205.005.00050
    - Policy Guide for Refugee Issues, 2009-07; MS205.005.00051; Humanity United
    - The Breakup of the Soviet Union and the Russian Diaspora, 2009-07; MS205.005.00052; Humanity United
  - Security arrangements, 2009; MS205.005.00053
    - India and Pakistan: Mass Movement of Refugees Following National Partition, 2009-11; MS205.005.00054
    - Policy Guide to Security Issues, 2009-12; MS205.005.00055
    - Serbia and Montenegro: Military Dissolution after Secessino from a Fragile Union, 2009-12; MS205.005.00056
    - Soviet Army: Dissolution of a Republic and its Army, 2009-12; MS205.005.00057
  - Water, 2009; MS205.005.00058
    - Indus Water Treaty, 2009-07; MS205.005.00059; Humanity United
    - The Jordan's Joint Water Committee, 2009-07; MS205.005.00060; Humanity United
    - The Mekong River Commission, 2009-07; MS205.005.00061; Humanity United
    - Nile Waters Agreements, 2009-07; MS205.005.00062; Humanity United
    - Policy Guide for Water Issues, 2009-07; MS205.005.00063; Humanity United